I will demonstrate my
superiority to everyone here.
（赤司(あかし)）
身分の違いを教えてやろう
この場にいる者 すべてに…
（火神(かがみ)）待ちやがれ 赤司！
Wait, Akashi!
つっ！ そんな…
No way!
（日向(ひゅうが)）止めろー！
Stop him!
（日向･伊月(いづき)）あ…
（黒子(くろこ)･木吉(きよし)）うぉぉぉぉ！
Your defeat is absolute.
オマエたちの敗北は絶対だ
Why Don't You Give Up
（氷室(ひむろ)）12点差
They're down 12 points.
Akashi's defending from even farther back.
赤司は今までより
相当 深い位置で守ってる
（氷室）
恐らく タイガ同様—
Like Taiga, his defensive
range is probably enormous.
ディフェンスエリアも
桁違いに広い
The other four are matching that and—
他の４人も
それに合わせて…
No.
（紫原(むらさきばら)）いや…
（氷室）はっ
After all the mistakes they've made,
Akachin expects nothing from the others.
（紫原）
あんだけの失態の連続
赤ちんは もう周りに
何も期待してないと思うよ
What? You mean...
まさか
ディフェンスも１人で…
He's defending alone, too?
No way. We're already within
Akashi's defensive range?
（伊月）ウソだろ
この位置で
もう 赤司の守備範囲!?
（若松(わかまつ)）スティールからの速攻!?
A steal into a fast break!
Kagami!
火神！
Focus! He must be stopped!
（火神）集中しろ
しがみついてでも止めるんだ！
（火神）うくっ…
Damn you!
えいっ！
The way you struggle is laughable.
滑稽な あがきだ
オマエは そこで
はいつくばっていろ
Stay there on the ground.
（観客１）決まったー！
He made it!
（観客２）赤司 君臨ー！
Akashi is dominating!
（白金(しろがね)）う…
（洛山(らくざん)選手たち）あ…
Sei-chan...
（実渕(みぶち)）征(せい)ちゃん…
Watch for threes while we're on defense.
（赤司）ディフェンスのとき
スリーには警戒しておけ
Even you can handle that.
オマエたちでも
それぐらいはできるだろう
な… そんな…
What?
（葉山(はやま)）赤司…
Akashi!
I expect nothing from you.
別に
期待はしていない
できなければ それも—
If you can't do it, then I will.
僕がやるだけのことだ
The greatest threat on offense
and defense is Emperor Eye.
（今吉(いまよし)）オフェンスにしろ
ディフェンスにしろ—
とにかく最大の脅威は
エンペラーアイや
What?
If Akashi has abandoned his teammates,
赤司に もう—
味方を頼るつもりが
ないんやとしたら—
then it's like the time
we played against Seirin.
誠凛(せいりん)が ウチとやった
状況と似とる
Single combat between
two players in the Zone.
（今吉）ゾーンに入ったもん同士の
一騎打ちや
That was an even contest, but Akashi
is completely overpowering him.
あんときは
ほぼ互角やったが—
今は赤司が完全に圧倒しとる
相手の動きを見てから動く
反射では—
Reacting to your opponents movements
can never beat predictions.
予知を超えることはできん
Out of bounds, black ball!
（審判）
アウト･オブ･バウンズ 黒ボール！
ハァ ハァ…
It's no use.
（火神）クソッ ダメだ…！
どうやっても今のオレじゃ
これ以上のプレーはできない…
I can't play any better in my current state!
ゾーンに入って
今 オレは水の底まで来てる
I've entered the Zone and
reached the bottom, but...
けど…—
そこに見えてる新しい扉が
どうしても開けられない！
I can't open the new door I see there.
前にいるヤツをどかさなきゃ…
I need to move the guy
standing in front of it.
待ってるだけじゃ
絶対 開かない！
It'll never open if I just wait!
どうすりゃいいんだ！
どうすりゃ…
What am I supposed to do?
Kagami-kun...
（黒子）火神君
（火神）あ…
黒子…
Kuroko.
Why don't you give up?
諦めませんか？ 一度
Why would you say that now, Kuroko?
何 言ってんだ 黒子？
ここまで来て…
試合を諦めるということでは
ありません
I'm not telling you to give up on the game.
火神君だけで戦うことをです
I mean give up on fighting alone.
託すとは言いましたが—
I said I was counting on you, but it
could be too heavy a responsibility.
それが重すぎることも
あると思います
もし今 そうだったら—
If that's the case, let me help you carry it.
ボクも 一緒に
背負わせてくれませんか？
そんなこと…
オレだけで大丈夫だ！
I can handle it myself!
もう少しで… あ…
I'm almost...
No, you're wrong.
（火神）
違う　そうじゃねぇだろ？
Crying that the door won't
open won't get us anywhere.
扉が開かないことを
嘆いても始まらねえ
We've got to do whatever we
can with it still closed.
開かない状況でやれることを
やるしかねえんだ
Fine. I accept your help.
分かった
じゃあ やっぱ
手伝ってもらうわ
Let's do this together.
やろうぜ ２人で…
We'll beat Akashi!
赤司を倒すぞ！
（伊月）頼むぜ 黒子 火神！
We're counting on you, Kuroko and Kagami.
With his Emperor Eye and the Zone,
エンペラーアイを使い—
かつ ゾーンに入った赤司の
守備範囲は紫原以上…
Akashi's defensive area is
larger than Murasakibara's.
それなら！
So...
They're passing the ball around,
outside his range!
（観客）
守備範囲外からの高速パス！
Yes!
よし！
（根武谷(ねぶや)）チィッ！
Go!
（小金井(こがねい)･リコ）いけぇー！
（高尾(たかお)）
これを決められたら終わりだ！
If he makes this, it's over!
Stop him!
（降旗(ふりはた)）止めてくれ！ 頼む！
Kuroko, Kagami!
（降旗）黒子！ 火神！
Kagami's in front?
（赤司）火神が前に？
ダブルチームではないのか？
They're not double-teaming me?
テツヤが 僕と火神の動きに
ついてこられるわけはない…
Tetsuya can't keep up with me and Kagami.
Even if he has an unexpected
plan, I can see the future.
仮に想定外の手を
たくらめていたとしても—
僕には未来が見える
エンペラーアイを
出し抜くことなど—
No one can beat my Emperor Eye!
何人(なんぴと)たりとも できはしない！
くうっ…
赤司君と火神君の差…
The difference between you and
Akashi-kun is the Emperor Eye.
それはエンペラーアイが
あるか ないかです
So I'll make up the difference
by becoming your "eye."
ならば…—
ボクが その差を埋める
“目”になります
（火神）右！
Right!
（１年生たち）うわぁー！
（赤司）バカな… ありえない！
What? Impossible...
なぜ オマエが僕より早く
僕の行く先にいる!?
How did you get there before me?
一体どうやって!?
How did he do it?
Kurochin wasn't looking at Akachin.
（紫原）黒ちん 今 赤ちんのこと
見てなかったね
How, then?
じゃあ何を!?
Kuroko was looking only at Kagami.
（緑間(みどりま)）黒子は今
火神だけを見ていた
He predicted Kagami's movements.
火神の動きを予知したのだよ
And he moved in the opposite direction.
そして火神と逆方向に動いた
It allowed him to catch up to Akashi,
who predicted Kagami's movements.
それによって—
火神の動きを予知した赤司に
追いついた
It's different from Emperor Eye.
（日向）エンペラーアイとは違う
The observation skills
he honed for Misdirection
ミスディレクションのために養った
観察眼と—
and the time they've spent playing
together allowed him to pull it off.
ずっと 一緒に戦った
チームメートだからできた芸当だ
（伊月）敵には使えない
He can't use it on opponents.
使えるのは—
He can only use it on allies with whom
he's spent time developing a solid rapport.
強固な信頼を築くだけの
時間を費やした味方にのみ
That rapport allowed him to see farther
into the future than Akashi.
（木吉）だが
その信頼があったからこそ—
赤司よりも さらに
一瞬 遠い未来まで見えた
（日向）仲間の未来を見る
黒子だけのエンペラーアイ！
Predicting the future of his allies,
Kuroko's very own Emperor Eye!
Yes!
（誠凛部員たち）やったー！
よぉし！
All right!
Counterattack!
（河原(かわはら)）逆襲だー！
You're kidding, right?
ウソでしょ!?
Stop them, Kotaro!
止めて 小太郎(こたろう)！
（１年生たち）抜いた！
He passed him!
Go!
（降旗）いっけー！
（火神）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
（赤司）ターンオーバーだと…
A turnover?
And I...
まさか この僕が…!?
I let it happen?
やあっ！
He's fast!
速い！
ロールでタイガのスピードが
緩んだ一瞬に—
He caught up in the second
Taiga's roll slowed him down!
追いついた！
（黛(まゆずみ)）赤司！
Akashi!
I can stop him with Emperor Eye!
（黛）
エンペラーアイなら 止められる！
What?
Tetsuya?
テツヤ…
（根武谷）アリウープ!?
An alley-oop?
（赤司）
ふざけるな　絶対は僕だ
Don't be absurd. I am absolute!
I must not lose!
負けることなど
絶対にあってはならない！
Make the shot, Kagami!
（誠凛一同）決めろ 火神ー！
（火神）ああ 任せろ
決めるさ！
Leave it to me. I'll make it!
I'm carrying the team's
hopes on my shoulders!
みんなの思いをしょってんだ！
I will make this shot!
絶対に決めてみせる！
うおあああああ！
（誠凛部員たち）
うおお！ 決まったぁー!
He made it!
ウソ… でしょ？
No way.
Sei-chan...
征ちゃんが…
Rakuzan
Seirin
He finally did it by supporting
Kagami with his pseudo Emperor Eye.
（高尾）ついに やりやがった
火神を擬似的なエンペラーアイで
サポートして…
Yes.
Kuroko's actions are surprising.
黒子は驚くべきことを
やっているのだよ
And Kagami is moving without
thinking about Kuroko.
そして 火神は—
黒子のことを
あえて考えずに動いている
すべてを委ねた上で
全開で動くなど—
Entrusting yourself completely
to someone and playing all-out
深い信頼がなければ不可能だ
is impossible without a deep level of trust.
They beat Emperor Eye precisely
because of who they are.
火神と黒子だからこそできた
エンペラーアイ破り
Is this the first time he's been beaten
this badly since starting high school?
しかし 彼が
ここまでやられたのは—
もしかして
高校で初めてじゃないか？
No.
いや…
The last time was probably when
we played in middle school.
たぶん オレと中学のころ
やったとき以来だよ
Akashi           Murasakibara
And ultimately, Akachin won that battle.
しかも その勝負も
結局 最後は赤ちんが勝ったし—
それ以前も
負けたとか聞いたことない
I haven't heard of him losing before then.
Akashi                       Murasakibara
But Akachin tried to score and failed,
and he tried to stop them but couldn't.
けど今 赤ちんは
点を取ろうとして取れず—
止めようとして
止められなかった
だから初めてじゃないかな 赤ちん
So it's probably the first
time, not just in high school,
高校どころか—
but in his life that Akachin's
experiencing defeat.
生まれて初めて
負けを感じてる
（日向）リバン！
（木吉）おお！
Rebound!
Akashi missed?
赤司が外した!?
Is the previous play still bothering him?
まさか
さっきのプレーを引きずって…
（青峰(あおみね)）初めて見んな
あんな赤司は…
I've never seen Akashi like this.
今までにないほど
心が乱れてやがる
He's less composed than he's ever been.
動揺 イコール雑念だ
He's unsettled, which means he's distracted.
He's leaving the Zone.
ゾーンが解けてやがる
（火神）ていっ！
He made it!
（福田(ふくだ)）決めたー！
We're down ten points!
Rakuzan
Seirin
（河原）ついに10点差だ！
（降旗）いける いけるぞ！
We can do it! We can win!
（日向）えいっ！
（赤司）限界だな
You're at your limit.
（赤司）ふざけるな！
僕が負けるなどありえない！
Don't be absurd! I can't lose!
Give up. You can't win anymore.
（赤司）諦めろ…
オマエでは もう勝てない
（赤司）黙れ！ 僕は勝つ
Shut up! I will win.
I have until now, and I always will!
今までも… そして これからも！
Okay, defense! Stop this shot!
よーし ディフェンス！
１本 止めるぞ！
Yeah!
（高尾）にしても—
I had no idea Akashi was this fragile.
赤司に ここまで
もろい面があるとはな
エンペラーアイを破られたのは—
The defeat of his Emperor Eye
must've been a shock, but...
確かに
ショックだったんだろうけど…
な… パス!?
A pass?
赤司がワンマンをやめた!?
Akashi stopped playing alone!
（実渕）ひっどいパスね もう！
What an awful pass.
It's like receiving the ball from a stranger.
まるで別人から受けてるみたい！
This is Heaven. But this shot...
（日向）くっ “天”のシュート！
だが これは…
うあっ！ 走れ！
Run!
Go!
（降旗）いけぇー！
ぐうっ！ うおっ…
（葉山）…って おい!?
What? You're slow getting back!
戻りおっせーよ
マジ なんだよ？ 赤司！
What's going on with you, Akashi?
えいっ
ふあっ！
（１年生たち）やったぁー！
Yeah!
（河原）おーし！
Yes!
ハァ… くぅ つっ！
であああ！ ふん！
（１年生たち）
うおおおー！ 決まった！
He made it!
We finally caught up to Rakuzan!
（福田）
とうとう洛山の背中をつかんだ！
We're just one basket behind!
（降旗）１ゴール差！
１ゴール差だぁー！
One basket behind!
Rakuzan
Seirin
（根武谷）ざけんな！
This is ridiculous!
A kid could've caught that weak pass!
んだ？ 今の小学生でも取れる
たりぃパスはよ！
You think that'll work now?
ここに来て
んなのが通ると思ってんのか!?
いいかげんにしろよ
赤司 てめえ！
I've had enough of your crap, Akashi!
（アナウンス）
白 タイムアウトです
White team timeout.
チィッ！
ハァ…
Kuroko?
黒子？
（白金）信じられん
I don't believe it.
Is Akashi this fragile a player?
赤司とは ここまで
もろい選手だったのか!?
点差が縮まっただけなら
動じるはずはない
The closing gap shouldn't
be enough to agitate him.
But he's shaken because they
defeated his trump card.
だが…—
ゆらいだ原因は—
あの２人に勝ちを決定づける
切り札を破られたことだ
その多大な精神的ダメージが
もたらした—
And that psychological damage
is creating discord on the team.
このままでは…
At this rate...
You're out, Aka—
メンバーチェンジだ 赤…
Wait.
（黛）ちょっと待ってください
ぶざまだな
You're embarrassing yourself.
（黛）慰めたり励ましたり
するとでも思ったか？
Did you think I'd console or encourage you?
しねーよ そんなこと
I'd never do that.
あんだけ偉そうなこと
言っといて—
After everything you said,
this is all you can do?
オマエ こんなもんか？
オレには
そうは思えないんだけどな
I don't think so.
You're nothing like the
man I met on the roof.
屋上で初めて会ったときとは
まるで別人だ
つーか… 誰だ オマエ？
In fact, who are you?
（赤司）僕は誰だ？
Who am I?
僕は誰だ？
I...
僕は… 僕は…
I am...
You are my weakness.
（赤司）オマエはオレの弱さだ
Born to a distinguished family,
（赤司）名門に生まれ
常に人の上に立ち—
always standing above others,
and obligated to win.
勝つことを義務づけられてきた
Even when you lost your mother, your only
repose, you weren't allowed to stop.
唯一の安息を与えてくれた
母を失っても—
立ち止まることなど
許されなかった
I was already beginning to tear apart then.
そのころ オレはもう—
引き裂かれ始めて
いたのかもしれない
バスケットボール
Basketball.
The anchor my mother left me.
母の残してくれた
よりどころ
As long as I kept winning,
my stern father allowed me to play.
厳格な父も 勝利する限り—
バスケに打ち込むことを
許してくれた
The Teiko basketball team's practices
were hard, but not painful.
帝光(ていこう)バスケ部の練習は
ハードだが苦ではなかった
それ以上に
思う存分バスケができ—
More than that,
I enjoyed the ability to play all I
liked and spend time with friends.
仲間と過ごす日々が楽しかった
そして 果たした 全中二連覇
Then we won our second national championship.
It would've been impossible with anyone else.
他の誰とも不可能だった
It happened because I had them. But...
彼らとだから かなえられた
だが…—
あるときからチームは
勝利至上主義へと傾いていく
The team began emphasizing victory.
時を同じくして—
At the same time,
their talents began to blossom.
彼らは次々と自らの才能を
開花させ始めた
その成長は—
Their growth planted the fear
that I'd be unable to keep up.
手に負えなくなることへの
恐怖となり—
Believing they would leave me
behind, fear turned to panic.
置いていかれることへの
焦りとなった
I, Akashi Seijuro, lost?
（赤司）オレが…—
赤司征十郎(せいじゅうろう)が負ける…
That's impossible. It cannot be.
ありえない
そんなことは
あってはならない…！
（赤司）勝利によって得たものは
敗北によって失われる
What is gained through victory
is lost through defeat.
オレは
最も強くあらねばならなかった
I had to be the strongest to
continue playing with them.
彼らとバスケを続けるために…
That's right. That's why...
そうだ　だから…
Who are you?
君は誰ですか？
I'm Akashi Seijuro, of course.
僕は赤司征十郎に
決まっているだろう
That's why I was born.
（赤司）だから 僕が生まれた
They followed me once again.
僕は再び彼らを従えた
全中三連覇も訳のないことだ
A third championship was easy enough.
It was a thorough victory.
完膚なきまでの勝利
I was absolute.
絶対は僕だ
Things were the same once
they became opponents.
彼らが敵となっても
同じことだ
I will continue proving my strength.
僕は僕の強さを証明し続ける
So you don't need me?
だから オレなど必要ないと？
That's right. You stay here forever.
そうだ
オマエはここにいろ　永遠に！
そのつもりだった
I meant to.
But the scent of defeat is making you crack.
だが今 敗北の予感が
オマエをきしませている
You know nothing!
何が分かる！
弱者に成り下がった オマエに！
You allowed yourself to be weak!
Yes. I didn't understand.
ああ
分かっていなかったのだろう
I was trying to save it by winning.
オレは勝つことで
つなぎ止めようとした
かけがえのないものを
Something irreplaceable.
I didn't know what else to do.
それ以外に
方法を知らなかった
その弱さが オマエを生んだ
That weakness gave birth to you.
Desiring only victory
and abandoning all else,
勝つことのみを求め
それ以外を切り捨て—
I lost sight of why I wanted to be stronger.
何のために
強くあろうとしたのかを見失った
And now you're about to
make the same mistake.
そして 今—
オマエは同じ過ちを
繰り返そうとしている
オレたちの罪は
決して消えはしないだろう
Our guilt will stay with us forever.
I thought it couldn't hurt to lose.
敗北するなら
それもいいと思っていた
But it seems I was wrong.
だが やはり
そうはいかないようだ
It's because we're playing Kuroko.
相手が黒子だったからかな
We can't suppress our impulse to win.
（赤司）
勝ちたい衝動が抑えきれない
（赤司）誰とは心外だな
How dare you ask who I am?
You're...
オマエ は…
I'm Akashi Seijuro, of course.
オレは赤司征十郎に
決まっているだろう
Preview
I can't back down now.
（赤司）ここで
下がるわけにはいかない
Are you back to normal?
（黛）調子は戻ったのかよ？
（赤司）ああ 目が覚めた
Yes, my eyes are open.
改めてオレに力を貸してほしい
I want you to lend me your
strength so we can beat Seirin.
誠凛に勝つために
It Was You
（黛）フッ… オレだって
負けたくはないからな
I don't want to lose, either.
I'll play as hard as I can.
思い切りいくだけだ